The courage to do the impossible lies in the hearts of men.
Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World is a
adventure, drama, war film directed by Peter Weir.
After an abrupt and violent encounter with a French warship inflicts severe damage upon his ship, a captain of the British Royal Navy begins a chase over two oceans to capture or destroy the
enemy, though he must weigh his commitment to duty and ferocious pursuit of glory against the safety of his devoted crew, including the ship's thoughtful surgeon, his best friend.
Captain Jack Aubrey, played by Russell Crowe.
Dr. Stephen Maturin, played by Paul Bettany.
1st Lt. Thomas Pullings, played by James D'Arcy.
Mr. Allen, Master, played by Robert Pugh.
Preserved Killick, Captain's Steward, played by David Threlfall.
Midshipman Hollom, played by Lee Ingleby.
Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World is a 2003 American epic period war-drama film
co-written, produced and directed by Peter Weir, set during the Napoleonic Wars.
The film's plot and characters are loosely adapted from novels in author Patrick O'Brian's
Aubrey–Maturin series, which includes 20 completed novels of Jack Aubrey's naval career.
The film stars Russell Crowe as Aubrey, captain in the
Royal Navy, and Paul Bettany as Dr.
Stephen Maturin, the ship's surgeon.
This was the second onscreen collaboration for Crowe and Bettany,
who previously co-starred in 2001's A Beautiful Mind.
The film was a personal project of 20th Century Fox executive
Tom Rothman, who recruited Weir to direct.
Filming took place on the open sea, on replica ships in the water
tanks of Baja Studios, and in the Galápagos Islands.
The film, which cost US$150 million to make, was a co-production of 20th Century Fox, Miramax
Films, Universal Pictures, and Samuel Goldwyn Films, and released on November 14, 2003.
The film received critical acclaim and grossed $212 million worldwide.
It garnered Weir the BAFTA Award for Best Direction.
At the 76th Academy Awards, the film was nominated in ten
categories, including Best Picture and Best Director.
It won Best Cinematography and Best Sound Editing.
The film explores themes of ship, navy, based on
novel or book, surgeon, royal navy.
The tone is dark and emotional.